usp.org 2019-12-02

# Privacy Policy | USP

USP respects the privacy of customers and visitors accessing this website and other websites maintained by USP, and takes seriously its responsibilities regarding the privacy and security of customer information and visitor information. USP reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to the Privacy Policy shall be announced via this website.

USP defines “personal data” to mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an “identifiable natural person” is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. USP may collect personal data including, but not limited to, your name, title, employer, address, telephone number, and email address. USP collects personal data from you through the use of registration forms, direct personal contact with you, and each time you email USP your details.

USP uses your personal data only when and where it is necessary to do so because it is relevant to USP's dealings with you or where USP has your consent to do so. This includes, but is not limited to, invoicing you for products and services you buy from USP, customer service, and network management. Purposes for which USP may use your personal data include direct marketing of USP products and services and customer surveys. USP will not disclose or share your personal data with any other party without your express consent, unless this is necessary to provide the services or products which you requested when providing us with your personal data, or as required by law. Aggregate data which has been de-identified may be used by USP and by third parties to track usage of USP's websites and applications. USP will not sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties.

You understand and agree that perfect security does not exist anywhere, including on the Internet. When you send credit card information to USP over the Internet, USP encrypts this information between your computer and our server. Other information you send to USP, including email messages, will not be encrypted unless USP advises you otherwise. USP may use cookies on its websites. USP has technical and organizational security measures intended to prevent unauthorized or unlawful disclosure or access to, or accidental or unlawful loss of or destruction, or alteration or unauthorized disclosure of or access to, or other damage to your personal data. These measures are intended to ensure an appropriate level of security in relation to the risks inherent in the processing and the nature of the personal data to be protected.

USP only keeps your information for as long as we are either required to by law, or as is relevant for the purposes for which it was collected. You may contact USP at any time if you would like to correct, update, supplement or delete personal data. You may also contact USP at any time to opt-out of receiving communications from USP at the point where USP requests information about you. You may send email to [privacy@usp.org](mailto:privacy@usp.org), or you may send mail to the following postal address:

Privacy, USP  
12601 Twinbrook Parkway  
Rockville, MD 20852

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, please email USP at [privacy@usp.org](mailto:privacy@usp.org).

## USP Cookies Policy

To enhance your experience on USP’s websites, many of USP’s web pages use cookies. Cookies are small text files that are placed in your computer’s browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not provide your email address or other personal information unless you choose to provide this information to USP—for example, by registering for e-newsletters or completing a web form. Once you choose to provide personal information to a web page, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. A cookie is like an identification card. It is unique to your computer and can be read only by the server that gave it to you.

Analytics cookies store information about what pages people visit, how long they are on the site, how they got there, and what they click on. Information supplied by analytics cookies helps USP analyze the profile of visitors and provide them with a better experience. Analytics cookies do not collect or store personal information (for example, names or addresses), so this information cannot be used to identify individuals. USP does not allow analytics companies to use or share its analytics data.

Some areas of USP websites allow users to log in and retrieve personal information and account details. Some of these areas use a cookie in order to remember account information.

You may also find embedded videos from external sites such as YouTube or Vimeo. Cookies that come from other sites like YouTube but work on USP.org are third-party cookies and are governed by such third-party’s privacy policy. Visitors may learn about third-party cookies policies on the third-party website’s privacy pages.

If you want to control which cookies you accept, configure your browser to accept all cookies or to alert you every time a cookie is offered by a website’s server. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser options so that you will not receive cookies and you can delete existing cookies from your browser. You may find that some parts of this site will not function properly if you have refused cookies.

## Information Regarding the Promoting the Quality of Medicines Program

The information provided on this website is not official United States Government information and does not represent the views or positions of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) or the United States Government. For more information about USAID's Privacy and Security Policy, please visit <http://www.usaid.gov/privacy-policy>.

Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade, firm or corporation name is for the information and convenience of the site’s visitors, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the United States Government or USAID. The views and opinions of authors expressed herein do not necessarily state or reflect those of the United States Government or USAID, and shall not be used for advertising or product endorsement purposes.

With respect to the content of this site, neither the United States Government, nor USAID, nor their employees and contractors make any warranty, expressed or implied or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third party rights, title, and the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose with respect to content available from this website or other Internet resources linked from it. Additionally, neither the United States Government nor USAID assume any legal liability for the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of any information, product, or process disclosed herein nor freedom from computer virus, and do not represent that use of such information, product, or process would not infringe on privately owned rights.
